S-So, uh...
We just gained a new friend today!
This is Miss Lainie,
daughter of Baron Cyan.
Be nice to her, everyone!
Uh...
Oh, do forgive me. This calls for tea.
Please wait a moment.
Miss Lainie...
I've been informed of your circumstances,
and I have no feelings
on the matter whatsoever.
But I'm sure it still weighs on your mind.
I'm not sure if I should
condemn you or forgive you.
It's too complicated.
I'm sorry.
Please, no! There's nothing
you need to apologize for!
It was all my fault!
Miss Lainie, did you put me in that
situation with malicious intentions?
No, of course not!
I never meant any such thing!
In that case, I cannot hold you liable
for the misfortune you were born with.
You came here for your own reasons,
which left you in need of help, correct?
Which means I cannot very well
slap away these hands.
The Magical Revolution
of the Reincarnated Princess and the Genius Young Lady
So this is the girl I've heard about.
You have magicite in your heart, do you?
Tilty, Lainie is very sensitive.
Try not to scare her.
I hear you've captivated
many young noblemen.
How did...
Huh? What's wrong?
I see. If I hadn't been told in advance,
I'd have been in trouble.
Something made me feel
sorry for her just now.
Oh, so even people with broken
personalities are affected, huh?
Your fascination power
really is amazing, Lainie!
No, uh, I really have no idea what...
So you're just activating it instinctively.
It seems like inherent magic.
Actually, I would bet...
that's what it is, isn't it?
Ah... You thought so too, huh?
There aren't many people
with magicite inside them.
There's no doubt about it.
I'm going to go get that thing.
What is that?
A forbidden text.
A forbidden text?!
Um, what is a forbidden text?
They contain records of dangerous
ideas and techniques,
so reading them is forbidden.
What is something like that doing here?
Miss Anis brought it here.
I don't remember when.
Miss Anis...
Uh, yeah, well...
Let's put that aside for now.
This is a collection of research notes
left by a magician long, long ago.
That magician's goal was the
pursuit of the truth of magic.
But the path he followed was endless.
He would never reach its terminus,
even after spending his life on it.
So the magician decided to make
up for his insufficient lifespan
by using the lives of others.
But... how?
He used the power of magicite.
Not like my magic medicine...
but much more directly.
He embedded magicite that he'd
stolen directly into his own body
and turned into a monster himself.
And then he absorbed other people's lives.
You ladies heard stories about it
when you were little, didn't you?
Stories of one who tricked humans
to create more like him,
who deceived people under
the cover of night.
The frightening monster
spoken of in fairy tales...
The vampire.
Wait a moment. What are you talking about?
Were we not just discussing
the issue concerning Miss Lainie?
They say anyone whose blood is sucked
by a vampire becomes a vampire.
But according to that book,
it was actually a form of brainwashing.
Brainwashing?
In other words, the way a vampire
would create more like him
was to overwrite people's
awareness to suit him.
Our magician here had this thought:
If he were to create plenty of extras
who would inherit his ideology,
and if one of them should arrive at
the truth one day, that would suffice.
How vile.
A human using the power of magicite
to manipulate people's thoughts...
That's a story we've heard
somewhere recently, isn't it?
You mean I'm... a vampire?
Oh, well... maybe not so much a vampire,
but the descendant of one?
The forbidden text says magicite within
a person's body becomes hereditary,
so most likely, your mother's
mother's mother's... uh...
I mean, if you could learn
to control your own power,
that would actually be amazing!
Would it?
That sounds interesting. Let's experimen—
I mean, start training you right away.
You want to control the
magicite's power, don't you?
The flow of mana within you has stagnated.
Try doing exactly as I tell you.
O-Okay.
Okay. Not bad for your first time.
We'll stop here for today.
Thank you so much.
Huh? Lainie, your eyes...
Huh?
H-Huh? What is this? My teeth...
Your teeth?
Whoa! Fangs!
Well, Lainie?
Do you feel like you can keep
your fascination power in check?
Oh... Yes!
It's as if a fog I had within me
just cleared up...
I feel like I can clearly understand
how to use my power now!
The vampire magicite has been activated.
Just as I thought.
Everything's up to you now, Lainie.
In her case, having magicite within her body
had become a matter of course.
Leaving it inactive within her
was actually unhealthy.
So now that the flow of mana
within you has been activated,
Those two are incredible.
you should be able to control it
at will from now on!
It doesn't feel as if Lainie
is doing anything right now.
Which probably means...
Euphie? Something wrong?
No, nothing.
Oh, right. I need to return
this to the library.
But I'd be bored going by myself.
Miss Anis, I'm going to borrow
Lady Euphyllia for a bit.
Huh?
Well...
So?
Huh?
You were giving me quite
a serious look back there.
Is there something you'd like to say to me?
Uh, not particularly...
Are you jealous?
Wait, what's her deal?
Does she not even realize it?
Is that how I looked?
I'd like to know what else
it could have looked like.
I see.
So I was jealous.
Ugh, you're such a pain to deal with!
Just what are you to Miss Anis?
I'm... her assistant.
I'm asking if you really see
yourself as her assistant!
Oh, don't make that face at me.
You make it look like I'm the bad guy.
The reason Miss Anis
took you as her assistant
was to restore your lost honor, was it not?
She achieved that goal when she defeated
the dragon, and on top of that,
she went on to solve the mystery
of Lainie and the strife she caused.
So what reason do you have
to continue being her assistant?
I...
It's not as if I'm trying
to take away your role.
I help Miss Anis because I find her
magicology and magic tools fascinating,
but I have no intention of going along with
her foolish dream of becoming a magician.
Really?
Enough talking about me.
I'm asking about you.
What... about me?
For instance, when Prince Algard
becomes the next king,
he might exile Miss Anis to the remote
borderlands out of prejudice against her.
Would you be able to accompany her?
Of course. You can't give an immediate
answer in the heat of the moment.
What you say and do steers the fate
of the Magenta family, after all.
Miss Anis is a heretic.
If you stand by her with half-hearted
intentions, you'll regret it.
I suggest you give it some serious thought.
You're right.
Come in.
Miss Anis?
Is something wrong?
Huh? Oh, I don't really need anything...
I just thought you seemed kind of down.
What were you up to, Euphie?
Well, I suppose...
I was thinking about the future.
What does that mean?
Now that things have started to calm down,
I was pondering what comes next.
I see.
I don't want to be half-hearted.
Huh? What'd you say?
Nothing at all.
I was...
I was just wondering what it is
I really want to do.
Did you find your answer?
Why do you like magic so much?
Well, that came out of nowhere.
Hmm... All I can really say
is because I like it.
It's like being in love, I think.
Not that I'd know.
I want to fall in love like that, too.
Hey, Euphie... Can I sleep in here tonight?
U-Um...
Miss Lainie, is something the matter?
W-Well... I just, um...
Can I...
ask for your help again?
I don't mind.
Go ahead.
An impulse to drink blood?
Yes.
Well, we did activate
the magicite inside her.
I think that makes her consume
more mana than before.
And when her body feels low on mana,
it manifests in the form of
an impulse to drink blood.
Leave it to a vampire.
So she can take the mana from other
people's blood and make it her own.
Have you let her drink any?
Yes, Ilia has.
We offered ours, too, but she told us
to remember our positions.
I am truly grateful to Miss Ilia.
Princess.
Oh, Ilia.
Wait, what's wrong? Why the dark look?
I just received this.
It's from the Ministry of the Arcane.
Ugh...
What a pain.
What did that garbage ministry say?
They want Miss Anis to give a lecture.
A lecture? That's amazing, Miss Anis!
Oh, it's not that kind of thing.
Basically, they want me to explain
in front of a bunch of people
what I plan to do with the
materials from the dragon.
Really?
This is quite an aggressive letter.
Right? Who wants anything to do with that?
U-Um...
The elites in the Ministry of
the Arcane value tradition.
They're not fond of the princess's
magicology and magic tools.
They say it's not in line
with belief in the spirits,
and that it'll be a negative
influence on the people.
They just want to find fault with me
and take all my materials again.
So what are you going to do?
If you refuse to do the lecture
because it's a hassle,
it'll just raise undue suspicions
and lead to more nasty rumors.
And it won't just be you.
All those close to you will suffer for it.
I don't want that.
That said, though...
What should I do?
That dragon's materials are valuable.
I don't want to lose a single one of them.
Okay! I'll just have to come up
with a new product
that'll convince even
the Ministry of the Arcane!
Would those people be convinced
by anything a heretic princess says?
Good point.
Ugh, damn that Ministry of the Arcane!
Miss Anis...
Could you leave this matter to me?
Huh?
Greetings, ladies and gentlemen.
I am Anisphia Wynn Palettia,
your speaker for today.
Oh, dear. Not a very receptive crowd.
No kidding.
I will now give my presentation
explaining how I intend
to use the materials
from the dragon I defeated.
However...
Before I get started, I'd like you
to take a look at this magic tool.
A magic tool? Part of that shady
business you call "magicology"?
Isn't mimicry of magic
sacrilege against the spirits?
This is my Witch's Broom,
a tool of flight that I invented
using magicology.
Using this, we can venture into the
unexplored territory we know as the sky.
Who would use such a thing other
than the mad princess? Ridiculous!
A princess who can't even use magic
is truly unworthy of our time.
Wow...
These old geezers aren't going to do
anything but find fault with me.
Miss Anis.
I am Princess Anisphia's assistant,
Euphyllia Magenta.
From this point onward, I will interject
my own opinions as a magician.
The genius daughter of Duke Magenta?
As you all know,
the power of flight is exceedingly
difficult to both acquire and master.
It has long been accepted that
not just anyone can freely fly.
But magic tools of flight make that possible.
I say this as one who has seen
Her Highness's research up close.
Anyone can fly, eh?
Hmm, how very intriguing.
This Witch's Broom has already been put
to practical use by its inventor.
However...
This shape is unacceptable.
It seems to reflect its inventor's tastes,
but it is problematic
from a safety perspective.
What? But brooms are what
witches are supposed to fly on.
Where is that "normal"?
Therefore, Her Highness set out
to develop a more versatile magic tool.
Please take a look at this.
What is that?
She calls it the "Airdra," representing
the concept of flying like a dragon.
With this, the pilot's body is as stable
as if they were riding a horse,
making it completely maneuverable and safe.
If her research progresses
to the point of mass production,
our kingdom's transportation network
will advance by leaps and bounds,
bringing with it the potential
for immense economic growth.
If that's the case...
We can't disregard this research.
In order to produce the Airdra,
the materials from the
dragon are indispensable.
Well, obviously.
The Airdra's unique structure
You came up with this tool specifically to
stop the dragon materials from being taken.
was inspired by the inherent
magic that dragons use
to keep their enormous bodies airborne.
Shut up, Tilty.
And as you all know,
different parts of a dragon act as catalysts
for different types of magic,
It does make sense.
so each of those materials
plays a part in guaranteeing
But in the face of the
ancient faith in the spirits...
the speed and safety of
each part of the Airdra.
This concludes my explanation of the
intended use of the dragon's materials.
That wasn't too bad.
Yeah. That's my Euphie.
However...
I fear that the Ministry
of the Arcane may view
such revolutionary research as sacrilege
to the spirits and the gods.
Wh-What?!
It absolutely is sacrilege!
Huh?
Wow, you're pushing that far?
No, I didn't ask her to!
Oh, this was her own decision?
Quite the assistant you've got there.
Knowledge of the world,
of reason, and of magic—
from a combination of these,
magicology is born.
It is a field of study,
not a practice intended to show
disrespect to faith or tradition.
It is true that the Her Highness's magicology
is a bold concept unlike any presently known
to us, and may appear incomprehensible.
But that is simply an expression
of respect toward the spirits.
No, in fact, it came to be only
because of that faith and tradition.
It is not due to a lack of talent
that Her Highness
did not receive the spirits' blessing.
It is because the spirits
recognized the talents she has.
That is what I want you all to understand.
Euphie...
I believe that now is the time
for us to walk in step with change.
I would like all of us to strive
for the future together,
along with the foundations
with which we have come this far.
My only wish is that today will be the
first step toward that wonderful future.
Thank you, Euphie.
Episode Seven
The Magic Lecture of the
Founder and the Assistant
Episode Eight
The Magic Definition of the
Monster and the Commoner